Here out at NFL owners' meetings, we are
joined by our owner, Mark Wilf. How are
you doing today? Doing great. Thank you.
Okay, well, we got to get into the into
the big questions. I know you have
spoken at length about your confidence
in Rob Brzezinski and what he brings to
the table in this interim role right
now. How did you evaluate what he was
able to do in a challenging off-season?
Well, I think I think between him and
Coach O'Connell, they've done a great
job putting our football coaching staff,
personnel staff together and really
going about the decision-making in an
intentional way, strategic way,
transparent, a lot of communication
going on. So, good decisions so far.
Right. I know you have a great
relationship with him. What is something
that he's done that may have impressed
you while he's taken on more of a
leadership role?
>> I just think the way he's bringing
people together and kind of getting
everyone's buy-in in terms of every
decision, including ownership, and
really being thoughtful and intentional
and patient in terms of making the moves
at the right time. And also, some of the
cap moves have been great. So, I think
we've cleaned up some of the challenges
we had there and we're ready to go for
the draft.
>> I bet. Well, before we get to that,
there were several moves made, most
notably Kyler Murray, a former
first-round [music] draft pick. What
excites you about adding more
competitive depth there in the
quarterback room? I think it's super
important. Obviously, quarterback, the
most important position in the in the
field and [music]
having a great quarterback room, J.J.
McCarthy, Kyler Murray, Carson Wentz
coming back after playing so well before
his injury last year and Max Brosmer.
So, we have a lot of great talent there,
good blend of all kinds of experience
and all kinds of talent. So, it's it's
going to be great. You mentioned the
draft and soon after that, you have also
said that you'll start the the new
general manager search. How does that
process begin? How do you see it playing
out?
>> already laying the groundwork. Again,
this is an ownership decision, very
important for the club. But right, you
know, we're really focused on the NFL
draft. We've got nine picks. We're
really excited about it. I think our
fans should be as well.
We're excited about that and focused on
that. And then right after the draft,
we'll get going in terms of interviews,
getting the best candidates, talking
through it and making sure we have the
right leader for our organization. Well,
we mentioned the draft and recently the
Vikings have announced that [music]
they're teaming up or partnering with
the Minnesota Sports and Events, as well
as US Bank Stadium, to put in a 2028 NFL
draft bid. So exciting.
How can that What kind of an impact does
that have on the organization, on and
off the field? Well, we saw in Super
Bowl 52 and Minnesota knows how to put
out big events. US Bank Stadium, the
premier stadium in the world. So, we
have all the attributes. We have a great
business community, a lot of support. We
have the CEOs of US Bank, Ecolab and
Medtronic along with us leading this
effort and I think we've got a great bit
put together and hopefully the NFL will
agree with us and get get us to the 2028
draft, but a lot of work ahead of us. On
a personal note, as an owner, what
[music] would it mean to you to be able
to bring that to the Twin Cities? Very
exciting. I mean, the community's been
so good to us as ownership, to the
Minnesota Vikings. We have great fans
and I think the fans deserve an NFL
draft. The community deserves it and
we're going to work on getting it to to
Minnesota in 2020.
>> Yeah, fingers crossed on that one. One
more thing before I let you go and enjoy
the beautiful weather here in Phoenix.
Girls flag football initiative has more
than doubled here in Minnesota as far as
the teams in the state. What about that
excitement, that exuberance for
participation impresses you the most?
Well, I just think the [music] the
empowerment girls flag football has
brought, the incredible explosive growth
all over the world, really, and the
confidence that it it gives young women
and and just the growth in Minnesota now
in over 100 schools, 19 of the top 20
cities in Minnesota have flag football.
So, hopefully Minnesota will join the 18
states that have already sanctioned it
as a full high school sport and we think
that's the sky's the limit as far as
getting
engagement in football. I hope so.
Really wish that was around when I was a
kid.
Thank you, Mark. Appreciate your time.
Thanks so much.